Carlos Silva

Electrical Engineer major in Electronics with experience in firmware development and embedded systems. My programming expertise lies in languages such as C, C++, and C#. In addition to my background as a developer in these languages, I have knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, and Web API, React, and Next.js.

I am a self-motivated and dedicated professional who is proficient at working both collaboratively and independently.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance, Lima (Remote) — *Embedded System & Frontend Developer*

NOV 2018 - PRESENT

Firmware development for embedded systems C/C++.

Firmware update, code optimization, and application of best practices based on MISRA and CERT C.

Dashboard development for data visualization in IoT systems React, Web API, MQTT.

Development of a smart traffic light management application based on Electron JS, React, and DevExtreme library. State management using

Creation of multiple websites using WordPress, Gatsby, and Next.js.

Email templates for email marketing campaigns.

Collaboration in the development of an employee and payroll management application based on SQL Server, C#, .NET Framework, Web API, MVC, and jQuery.

The Factory HKA, Caracas (Remote) — *Firmware Engineer*

MAY 2022 - AUG 2016

Firmware development for embedded systems used in tax solutions; tax printers, and transmission devices using C/C++, React, Web API.

Firmware migration to other architectures due to microcontroller scarcity using C/C++.

Desktop application development to update firmware on tax printers or transmission devices using C#.

Genialprojects, Lima (Remote) — Firmware Engineer

NOV 2016 - JAN 2018

Firmware development of a thermometer for temperature tracking and fever detection. An app for Android and iOS allows tracking of temperature, fever status and battery level. Historical data can be accessed and monitored through the Internet. The firmware can be updated over the air.

Lima, Perú +51 942-314-138

clsilva@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/carloslsilva

SKILLS

C, C++, C#
FreeRTOS
PIC, ARM Cortex M
HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
TypeScript, Web API
React, Next.js, Node.js
GIT

SOFTWARE

Linux (Debian derivatives)

LANGUAGES

English (Basic)
Spanish (Native)

The Factory HKA, Caracas — Firmware Engineer

MAY 2016 - NOV 2016

Firmware and management application development for a keyboard (SmartKey) designed to be used with fiscal printers, providing the functionality of a cash register.

EDUCACIÓN

UCV, Caracas — *Electrical Engineer major in Electronics*JULY 2016